<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>daniel-e blog</title>
    <description>Notes on machine learning, my activities on GitHub and more</description>
    <link>http://daniel-e.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://daniel-e.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Computing the determinant in Python in one (long) line of code</title>
        <description>
          
          Computing the determinant is one of the fundamental operations in linear algebra with many practical applications. The determinant can be used to compute the area of a parallelogram or to check if there exists a solution for a system of linear equations. The determinant is defined only for square matrices...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2015-12-15-compute-the-determinant-in-python-in-one-line-of-code</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2015-12-15-compute-the-determinant-in-python-in-one-line-of-code</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Averaging MNIST handwritten digits with Octave</title>
        <description>
          
          In this post we will see how the average digit of the MNIST database of handwritten digits looks like. The MNIST database of handwritten digits (see here) is a very popular dataset used by the machine learning research community for testing the performance of learning algorithms for the task of...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2015-10-19-averaging-mnist-handwritten-digits-with-octave</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2015-10-19-averaging-mnist-handwritten-digits-with-octave</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>k-Nearest Neighbors on MNIST digits with Octave</title>
        <description>
          
          TODO

        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2015-08-10-k-nearest-neighbours-on-mnist-digits-with-octave</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2015-08-10-k-nearest-neighbours-on-mnist-digits-with-octave</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MNIST database of handwritten digits for Octave</title>
        <description>
          
          In this post you will see how to convert the MNIST database of handwritten digits via rustml into a format that can be read with Octave. The MNIST database of handwritten digits (see here) is a very popular dataset used by the machine learning research community for testing the performance...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2015-07-25-MNIST-handwritten-digits-for-Octave</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2015-07-25-MNIST-handwritten-digits-for-Octave</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maximum GFLOPS for an element-wise matrix multiplication</title>
        <description>
          
          A question that often comes into my mind when doing computations with Octave or other numerical libraries is how good do they utilize the CPU. Recently I was interested in estimating the number of GFLOPS that can be achieved with Octave for the element-wise matrix multiplication. For an nxn matrix...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-31-maximum-gflops-element-wise-matrix-multiplication</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-31-maximum-gflops-element-wise-matrix-multiplication</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Octave matrix multiplication performance for different BLAS implementations</title>
        <description>
          
          Octave is a tool for doing linear algebra. When doing linear algebra one of the most fundamental operations is the matrix multiplication. A straightforward algorithm to do a matrix operation requires O(n³) multiplications. In 196 Strassen developed an algorithm for multiplying big matrices (n &amp;gt; 100 to 1000) which requires...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-27-octave-matrix-multiplication-performance-blas</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-27-octave-matrix-multiplication-performance-blas</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CPU Throttling apparently enabled</title>
        <description>
          
          When compiling ATLAS (Automatically Tuned Linear Algebra Software) on modern CPUs it may happen that you get the following error message: CPU Throttling apparently enabled! It appears you have cpu throttling enabled, which makes timings unreliable and an ATLAS install nonsensical. Aborting. This is because today most operating systems  turn...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-27-cpu-throttling-apparently-enabled</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-27-cpu-throttling-apparently-enabled</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Permission denied for lsof in Docker</title>
        <description>
          
          On my host system I have installed Linux Mint 17 and on that host I’m running Docker with Ubuntu 14.10. Recently I wanted to call lsof in a Docker container and I got the following permission denied error: root@ada77fe6ef60:/tmp $ lsof -p 751 COMMAND PID USER FD TYPE DEVICE SIZE/OFF...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-26-permission-denied-for-lsof-in-docker</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-26-permission-denied-for-lsof-in-docker</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Octave performance - Ubuntu 14.10 vs Linux Mint 17 Qiana</title>
        <description>
          
          Recently I played around with Octave that I’ve installed on Ubuntu 14.10 running in a Docker container. The host system on which Docker is running is a Linux Mint 17 (Qiana). I was wondering whether there is a significant overhead induced by Docker when doing big matrix multiplications. So, I’ve...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-24-octave-performance-ubuntu-14-10-vs-linux-mint-17-quiana</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://daniel-e.github.io/2014-12-24-octave-performance-ubuntu-14-10-vs-linux-mint-17-quiana</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
